5 Từ vựng TOEIC Part 5
Bài 2 - Tiền tố AD-
ADEQUATE
/ˈædɪkwət/ - adjective
đủ, thỏa đáng
The budget is adequate for the project.
Ngân sách đủ cho dự án.
adequate = enough, không phải excellent
Collocations: adequate resources, time, supply
ADHERE
/ədˈhɪr/ - verb
tuân thủ, bám vào
All employees must adhere to company policies.
Tất cả nhân viên phải tuân thủ chính sách công ty.
Luôn dùng với TO → adhere to
Collocations: adhere to rules, guidelines, policies
ADJACENT
/əˈdʒeɪsənt/ - adjective
kế bên, liền kề
The parking lot is adjacent to the building.
Bãi đỗ xe nằm kế bên tòa nhà.
Luôn dùng với TO → adjacent to
Collocations: adjacent to, adjacent building, room
ADJUST
/əˈdʒʌst/ - verb
điều chỉnh
Please adjust your schedule accordingly.
Vui lòng điều chỉnh lịch trình cho phù hợp.
adjust = tinh chỉnh, không phải thay đổi hoàn toàn
Collocations: adjust settings, to changes, price
ADMINISTER
/ədˈmɪnɪstər/ - verb
quản lý, điều hành
She administers the department efficiently.
Cô ấy quản lý phòng ban hiệu quả.
administer formal hơn manage
Collocations: administer a program, test, funds
QUIZ TIME!
Q1: The budget is _____ for the project.
Đáp án: ADEQUATE
Q2: All employees must _____ to policies.
Đáp án: ADHERE
Q3: Từ nào nghĩa là kế bên?
A. adequate  B. adhere  C. adjacent  D. adjust
Đáp án: C - ADJACENT
TÓM TẮT: 5 từ tiền tố AD-
adequate, adhere, adjacent, adjust, administer
LIKE - SUBSCRIBE - BẬT THÔNG BÁO
Bài 3: admit, adopt, advance, advertise, advise